

+2 010 209 238 57 ibnfahmi5004@gmail.com in linkedin.com/in/ibnfahmi Bē behance.net/ibnfahmi

Adobe Photoshop

Summary

I'm a product designer with 6+ years of experience, specializing in FinTech and marketplaces. I've worked with companies like Money Fellows, 4Sale, and Sarmady, leading design systems, enhancing user experiences, and mentoring teams.

I focus on scalable, cost-effective design solutions that drive business growth and improve usability. Whether refining interfaces or collaborating crossfunctionally, my goal is always to make products look great and work even better.

Skills and Tools

Figma

Prototype Adobe Illustrator Adobe After effects Adobe XD Design tokens HTML CSS SASS VS code Communication Collaboration User research **UX** strategy Design system Agile

Principal product designer

Work experience

4Sale | 2024-Present

4Sale is one of the largest online marketplaces in the Middle East, and easily

O Cairo, Egypt

Kuwait's largest marketplace. As the team UI advocate I contribute to design systems, style guides, and UI

- component libraries, Establishing design patterns, guidelines, and standards for consistent and scalable design across products. Collaborate with the cross-functional squad (Hunters) on new products, services,
- and features, such as highlighting seasonal items and categories to increase sellers' views and clicks by implementing visually appealing and user-friendly solutions. Additionally, align on design requirements and effectively communicate design concepts to stakeholders.

Money Fellows | 2022-2024

Money Fellows is a digital money circle mobile application that allows users to save money and get access to a lump sum payout ahead of time. It is the largest money

Principal UI designer

Cairo, Egypt

circle app in Egypt, with over 4 million users. · I contribute to design systems, style guides, and UI component libraries, Establishing design patterns, guidelines, and standards for consistent and

- scalable design across products. Provide leadership and mentor UI design teams, fostering high-quality, user centered designs and promoting design best practices within the organization.
- · Collaborate with cross-functional teams to align on design requirements and effectively communicate design concepts to stakeholders.
- Senior product designer

Work with the product team to develop intuitive user experiences (UX) for fintech

products. This includes creating user flows, wireframes, and interactive

Money Fellows | 2020-2022

Cairo, Egypt

- prototypes to optimize user navigation and task completion in the financial · I designed the UI to align with UX principles and branding guidelines, creating visually appealing interfaces that convey trust, security, and financial expertise.
- · I collaborate with cross-functional teams, presenting design concepts and gathering feedback to ensure alignment and valuable insights from various
- perspectives.

A full-service digital media agency in Egypt that has been creating unique, regionally relevant, and trusted content in both Arabic and English since 2001.

Senior UI/UX designer

· I designed intuitive and visually appealing user interfaces, logos, illustrations, and

Sarmady - a Vodafone company | 2019-2020

Cairo, Egypt

other visual assets to deliver engaging and memorable user experiences. · Actively collaborated with cross-functional teams, ensuring alignment and

- delivering cohesive designs that met project goals. • I incorporated user feedback and conducted research to ensure designs were
- user-friendly and met user needs.I maintained consistency with branding guidelines, paying close attention to detail in every design element. I focused on capturing the essence of the brand and creating designs that aligned with the
- company's brand identity. Senior graphic designer The Portal Agency | 2018-2019 Cairo, Egypt

The Portal is a Global Marketing Consultant and Software Development Agency located in New York, Dubai, Munich and Cairo with a core focus on creative, content,

· I actively led the design operations for all domains, including social media,

team of juniors and interns to ensure their productivity and success.

that met the clients' needs in Egypt and the MENA region.

Graphic designer

branding, web, and mobile app designs. I personally monitored and managed a

inside Egypt and outside with all kind of industries. · I supported the design team in creating and executing advertising campaigns

technology & e-commerce.

amg' Advertising | 2016-2017

Advertising agency, providing ATL, BTL, designs, and production services, working

Cairo, Egypt

Projects

https://www.figma.com/design/euc2ZX7J9EqCMjluAgqbag/mabsoot-Illustrations-

SAPPHIRE DS (Money Fellows DS) https://www.figma.com/design/swZcNdlqvUn3zAQP8SvYKp/SAPPHIRE-2.0?nodeid=1883-1792&t=s8XI6xonx6bqzQLc-1

Money Fellows join Circle flow

Mabsoot Rotate&Pose® illustration library

<u>Library-1.0-(Demo)?node-id=102-4932&t=VCzvOu1ZEC3D1eWr-1</u>

https://www.figma.com/proto/KX3OatdhJsFrqzirMz9VzU/New-Join-flow-%5BAPR-2023%5D?page-id=3355%3A44393&node-id=9081-57170&nodetype=FRAME&viewport=4685%2C3467%2C0.3&t=tq7VdBv6P6A0Ag27-1&scaling=scale-

down&content-scaling=fixed&starting-point-node-id=9081%3A57170

Money Fellows Payout investment product https://www.figma.com/proto/xlvvs1O3zDhjvSdGCTNmoF/Use-the-payout-as-

Mercato filgoal (Logo & UI)

https://mercato.filgoal.com/

investment?page-id=11963%3A57814&node-id=15133-68806&nodetype=CANVAS&viewport=1691%2C-96%2C0.52&t=n6eFO8zq2GU4LF33-1&scaling=scaledown&content-scaling=fixed&starting-point-node-id=15133%3A68806

Fantasy FilGoal (Logo & UI)

Elements of a UI Design

patterns

they evolve to be a new species?

https://ibnfahmi.medium.com/ consciousness-of-an-ai-can-theymurder-us-f9885a081a6

type=design&node-id=1%3A2&mode=design&t=IbTCjSBf9wE4u5wY-1

https://www.figma.com/file/idF0WYB3vysKSY6oHSnVYW/Fantasy-Prototype?

Certificates **Publications**

language, signifiers, and

certification/ibnfahmi/responsivehttps://ibnfahmi.medium.com/ web-design elements-of-a-ui-3d561111fb16

Enterprise Design Thinking Consciousness of an Al, can Co-Creator

https://www.credly.com/badges/ e68b89eb-0744-40cbbe1f-858ba77b1285? source=linked_in_profile

Responsive web design

https://www.freecodecamp.org/

~FreeCodeCamp

Enterprise Design Thinking

Practitioner ~IBM

~IBM

https://www.credly.com/badges/ ed9fc6f2-7dbe-4ac3-8cbccad087aa9493? source=linked_in_profile

Languages

English Arabic Intermediate Native

Education